[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trien tasa Advanced Training as you all
know I've already published 64 YouTube
videos covering beginners level
intermediate level and advanced level
concepts of tricentis tasa Automation
and from couple of videos on have
started teaching you the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of obstacles and how can
you solve those obstacles by using
tricentis tasa while automating your
test cases please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos don't forget to like and
share the video thank
you this is our lesson 65 in terms of
overall tricentis tasa automation
training and this is our obstacle
23 where I'm going to teach you about a
realtime
scenario where you need to solve an
obstacle by using click position method
with the help of offset horizontal
offset vertical
parameters by using trienes tasa while
automating your test case so now let us
understand inde detail what is the
obstacle that we are going to solve for
this is our obstacle list and our
today's obstacle is halfway the name of
the obstacle is halfway and which is
categorized as medium so let us go for
it and understand in detail what is the
obstacle that we are going to solve for
click in the right half of the button
that means so this is your click into my
right half button and you need to click
right half of the button that means
let's assume this is your
middle and you need to click right half
so if you click right half then you
solve this automation problem so if you
click on left half then that means your
automation problem is not successful so
you can see here see here here here and
then if you do this way now it is
successful that means you need to
click in the right half of the button so
how can we do
this let us go to our
notepad so we can Define
offset
per
operations
like
click or long
click that we use in trient
toas so how can we Define offset for
click open curly Braes
click open Square braces close Square
braces and again open Square braces
close Square braces and then close curly
braces so under these Square braces I'm
going to
Define offset
horizontal and then in other Square
braces I'm going to Define offset
vertical so now how can I define these
offset horizontal and vertical there are
two ways either you can use
pixels or you can
use or you can use
percentage so two ways you can Define
the offset horizontal or offset vertical
parameters so to solve this obstacle I'm
going to use percentage here so if I say
80% of offset horizontal that means your
horizontal
position to click by using Mouse is at
80% level and if I'm specifying offset
vertical as let's say 70% that means
vertically you're going to click
on object at exactly 70% of the position
vertical position and 90% of the
horizontal position so let us go to
triena and see how can we solve this
problem so as usual we're going to start
scanning all the objects
under
module folder called obstacles
folder right so we are capturing
objects in this particular folder for
every obstacle simply I'm going to right
click on this folder select scan and
select
application so this is my application
which I would like to scan select the
application and click on scan
so for this particular obstacle I just
need to capture only one button what is
that click into my right half select
this button and make sure the button is
uniquely identified I can see the
selected item is unique and
then and then let us rename this module
with the name of
obstacle and now save the module
and close the X scan let's go back to
tonasa so this is our module that we
have scanned just now so the least so
this last one obstacle
41038 you can see click into my right
half so now let us go to test case
section so we are capturing all the test
cases under obstacles folder so I'm
going to double click on this obstacle
folder
fer and here I'm going to create a new
test case under this test case folder
right
click create test case and provide the
name as same obstacle name and double
click on this now to automate the test
case you need to drag the module onto
your test
case so here as I told you I'm going to
solve this problem by using the offset
percentage so let's do one thing what
I'm going to use here open curly braces
click right so this is what I'm going to
use open curly
braces click close curly braces so
generally so generally we enter this key
to click on any button but when you
enter this click key you're not defining
the position where the
Mouse should click on this button on
what position it can click exactly at
middle of the button exactly at 50% of
the position 50% what is what do you
mean by 50% this is your 50% it starts
from 0 10 20 like that 50 and then 60 70
80 that means to solve this problem you
need to click between 50 and
100 or horizontal position what about
vertical position vertical you can
Define anything what you want right so
let me first Define horizontal position
here what I'm going to say open Square
braces close Square braces and here I'm
going to specify let's say
80%
80% you have to specify the symbol also
so right click on somewhere now it says
click 80% horizontal offset because the
first parameter that you enter is
horizontal so let me simply run this and
see what happens okay right click and
run observe closely the
position see here exactly 80% horizontal
position it clicked that means it
clicked on right half of
the button let's say if I do change
let's say if I change this position to
30% then what happens let's see right
click and run in
scratchbook see exactly it is clicking
at left position that's why your
automation problem is not
solved let's go back here now what I'm
going to do here now again I'm going to
Define two things I need to click on
right half I'm going to say this time 95
that means exactly
at end of the button is going to click
and I'm going to also Define the
vertical position vertical position what
I'm going to do I'm going to specify as
90% that
means horizontally it should click
exactly at almost right position and
vertically it almost should click at
bottom here if I specify 10 it's going
to click here but anyway let's run this
right click and run we'll see what
happens
see right side 90% And the vertical
position also it's clicking
here right so here it's it's almost
clicked here vertical position also 90
let me do one thing to solve this
problem this time vertically whatever
the position you want you can click
right so I'm going to change it as
10% but horizontally still I'm clicking
on left only sorry I'm clicking on right
only again now right click and
run see it is clicking on top vertical
position here and your horizontal
position is this side right so if I
don't specify any offsets here right
that means it's going to click exactly
horizontally middle and vertically also
middle 50% exactly you don't specify any
offset
hope you all understand how can we
perform click operation by using
percentage which means
orizontal offset horizontal off by using
offset horizontal and offset vertical
positions if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond to your queries hope you all
understand the concept of real time
scenario where you need to solve an
obstacle by us using the click position
with the help of offset horizontal and
offset vertical parameters by using
trienes
tasa please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos don't forget to like and share
the video thank you
[Music]